Guide to the Henry Raup Wagner Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Research Files, 1912-62; Series III; 6; (11 boxes)
  - "Buckingham Smith's Library", n.d. (Box 31, Folder 364)
  - Defoe items: Extracted from Catalogue of...library of the late George Chambers, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 364.1)
  - Eames, Wilberforce, 1935-38 (Box 31, Folder 365)
  - "The First Issue of Rumold Mercator's Map of the World", n.d. (Box 31, Folder 366)
  - Gemma of Friesland: "On the Principles of Astronomy and Cosmography", 1936 (Box 31, Folder 367)
  - Hodge, Frederick W., 1949 (Box 31, Folder 368)
  - "How to Give Collections to Libraries", 1954, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 369)
  - "The Journal of Captain James Colnett aboard the Argonaut" [Review], 1941 (Box 31, Folder 370)
  - "Land Legislation: Notes for a Bibliography"
    - Typescript (photocopy), n.d. (Box 31, Folder 371-74)
    - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 375)
  - "The Manila Galleon" [Review], 1940 (Box 31, Folder 376)
  - Mayer, Brantz: "History of the Mexican War", 1914 May 26 (Box 31, Folder 377)
  - Mexico: history of books and printing
    - Bibliographies of Mexican works, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 378)
    - "Mexican Codices": article, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 379)
    - "Mexican Codices": notes, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 380-82)
    - Printing in Colonial Mexico, 1935-45 (Box 32, Folder 383)
    - Printing in Provincias Internas, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 384)
  - "The Mutiny on the Conception and the Killing of Diego Becerra" (Box 32, Folder 385)
  - "Nolan Papers", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 386)
  - Padoucas: notes, 1918-24 (Box 32, Folder 387)
  - Portuguese Discovery of the Moluccas
    - Articles, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 388)
    - Notes and drafts (Box 32, Folder 389)
    - Maps
      See: Oversize, Box 35, folder 441
  - "The Rise of Prices in New Spain in the XVIth Century"
    - Typescripts, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 390-91)
    - Correspondence, 1940, 1944 (Box 32, Folder 392)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 393)
  - "Schoolcraft's Archives", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 394)
  - "Spanish Southwest 1795-1845", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 395)
  - Texas Bibliography
    - Bibliographic entries, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 396-401)
    - Bibliographic entries, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 402-05)
    - Notes, [ca. 1914] (Box 33, Folder 406)
    - Raines's Bibliography of Texas, 1896, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 407-08)
    - Photostats, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 409)
  - Wagner, Henry Raup
    - Letter of Introduction used in Mexico, 1912 Aug 12 (Box 33, Folder 410)
    - Photographs, 1953 Sep 27 (Box 33, Folder 411)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 412)
  - Yale University. Wagner's Mexican Collection
    This collection was donated/sold to Yale in 1916. These lists, produced by Wagner, accompanied the material.
    - Bibliographical Notes By Wagner: List I, 1552-1799, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 413-14)
    - Bibliographical Notes By Wagner: List I, 1800-1912, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 415-18)
    - Bibliographical Notes By Wagner: List II, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 419)
    - Bibliographical Notes By Wagner: List III, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 420)
    - Bibliographical Notes by Wagner: Miscellaneous lists, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 421-22)
    - Bibliographical Notes by Wagner: Boxes B-L, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 423-27)
  - "Zamorano Press Imprints", n.d. (Box 34, Folder 428)
  - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 429-30)
- Oversize, 2; (1 box)
  Oversize contains oversize material from Series I, II and III, in a parallel arrangement.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Pomona College Degree, 1935 (Box 35, Folder 431)
    - University of California Degree, 1949 (Box 35, Folder 432)
    - Yale University Degree, 1946 (Box 35, Folder 433)
  - WORKS FROM THE PUBLISHED WRITINGS
    - (9) California Imprints, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 434)
    - (49) "Three accounts of the Expedition of Fernando Cortés", 1928-29 (Box 35, Folder 435)
    - (64) The First Issue of the Los Angeles Star, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 436)
    - (124) Rise of Fernando Cortés (Box 35, Folder 437)
    - (135) Nueva Bibliografía del Siglo XVI, Suplemento to a las Bibliografías de Don Joaquín García Icazbalceta, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 438)
    - (148) "Marco Polo's Narrative becomes Propaganda" (Box 35, Folder 439)
    - (166) "Henri Ternaux", n.d. (Box 35, Folder 440)
  - RESEARCH FILES
    - Portuguese Discovery of the Moluccas: maps, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 441)